# Abraham Hernández Venegas

Senior Java Developer - Technical Lead / Remote

#### PROFILE

I have 9 years of professional experience in Software Development with Java, including 6 years of experience working with Microservices under the Spring Boot and Spring Cloud Frameworks, most of them in the financial sector. I have participated in multiple self-managed and multidisciplinary projects with the Agile Scrum framework.

### **EDUCATION**

August 2010 – Computer Engineering
December 2014 Universidad Autónoma del Estado de México

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

April 2024 - September 2024

**Banco Base** Senior Java Developer Polanco – Ciudad de México / Remote (Contractor)

Maintenance and development of new functionalities in the **Easy Credit Project in Banco Base**, a purely internal project of the bank that facilitates the generation of enterprise credit, composed of a hexagonal architecture of microservices in **Java 17** and **Java 20**, using as Frameworks **Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Spring WebFlux and Spring Security**, all this mounted on a cloud infrastructure such as **Docker** and **Kubernetes**, all automated with **Jenkins CI/CD**. For data storage we use relational databases like **MySQL** and in-memory databases like redis for caching. To maintain code quality we used **Sonar** with a coverage of 90% for it was necessary to comply with this coverage by applying unit tests with **JUnit 5** and **Mockito**. The development methodology was through **SCRUM**, an agile methodology.

January 2023 - April 2024

**GFT México - Sabadell** Senior Java Developer / Technical Lead Polanco - Ciudad de México / Remote

Maintenance and development of new functionalities leading the backend team of the **Banco Sabadell** mobile APP, made up of an **API Led** architecture of microservices in **Java 8**, **Spring Boot** and **Spring Cloud**, mounted on a cloud infrastructure such as **Docke**r and **Kubernetes K8**, all Automated with Jenkins CI/CD.



**S** 5!

55-16-19-17-38



abraham.hdz.v14@gmail.com



Texcoco, Estado de México

# SKILLS

Technical: Java 8, Java 11, Java 17, SpringBoot, SpringCloud, Spring Data, Spring WebFlux, Spring Security, Swagger, OpenAPI, JavaScript, Angular, TypeScript, Hibernate, JPA, HTML, CSS, Oracle, MySql, MongoDB, Tomcat, OpenShift, Docker, Git, SVN, Junit, Mockito, Jenkins, Sonar, Vercacode, Log4j, Maven, Gradle, Intellij, Android Studio, SCRUM, JIRA, Selenium, Cucumber, Redis, Rabbit MQ, Redis, Kubernetes K8, Kibana.

**Personal:** Self-taught, reliable, responsible, proactive, orderly, punctual, teamwork

### January 2019 - October 2022

**Kairos DS - Santander** Senior Java Developer / Technical Lead Santa Fe – Ciudad de México / Remote

TAP Santander Project; Member of Santander's Innovation area, working as a Java Middleware Developer in the digital factory. In charge of developing several modules, these being Microservices and libraries for SPEI transactions and the bank itself, each of the microservices that I have developed are in Java 8 with the Spring Boot and Spring Cloud Frameworks. During my stay in Santander I have used various technologies such as: OpenShift (PaaS) for MS deployment, Jenkins for deployment automation and continuous integration (CI, CD), through the **Sonar** tool to guarantee the quality of the Code, also through **Veracode** for code security analysis applying SAST and DAST analysis. Regarding **security**, symmetric and asymmetric encryption was implemented, such as AES and RSA, all this to guarantee that the sending of information travels safely, as well as authentication through JWT, being obtained and validated by the **OAUTH 2.0** server. In Databases we make use of Relational Oracle, MySql and non-relational such as MongoDB, as well as in-memory databases such as **Redis** and message queues with **Rabbit MQ**, this to further improve the speed of information response. During development we have good coding practices to follow, for this we apply the **TDD** methodology for unit tests under the **JUnit** and **Mockito** framework.

#### October 2018 - December 2018

Planet Media Senior Java Developer

Polanco, Ciudad de México

Maintenance and development of new features for a **SEMARNAT** project using technologies such as: JSP, Servlets, HTML, Spring Core, Hibernate, PrimeFaces and Oracle BD 10g.

#### April 2017 - October 2018

**Softtek – Banamex** Senior Java Developer

Col. Narvarte Poniente, Ciudad de México

- 1) IParticipated in a microservices development team for Banamex bank, moving legacy (monolithic) banking systems to microservices architecture, using tools and technologies such as: Spring Boot, Spring cloud, Spring DataGemFire, PCF (Pivotal Cloud Foundry), Jenkins, Sonar for code quality, Git, Java 8, SCRUM, Jira, Swagger, Junit, Mock, Eureka, REST services.
- 2) I participated in the Stock Exchange project (AcciTrade) for Banamex, generating new functions for the project and providing maintenance, using as technologies: Struts 2, JSP, HTML, Hibernate, JavaScript, Jquery, Ajax, SQL Server, WebLogic.

March 2016 - April 2017

**Everis** Mid-Senior Java Developer

Col. Juárez, Cuauhtémoc, Ciudad de México

I participated in a project for **TELCEL** developing new modules and maintaining the **Telcel Leasing** system, using as technologies: **Maven** for the generation, compilation and packaging of the system, **JSF** with **RichFaces** and **JavaScript** for the presentation layer, **Spring** for the control layer, **Hibernate** for the persistence layer, using the **Sonar** platform to measure the quality of the system and good programming practices.

## LANGUAGES

Spanish

English

#### INTERESTS

Read

Software Development

Mobile Apps

**New Technologies** 

Play Football Soccer

## SOCIAL NETWORK



https://www.linkedin.com/in/abraham-hernandez-venegas

#### January 2015 - February 2016

## **Softtek** Junior Java Developer

Col. Narvarte Poniente, Ciudad de México

I participated in an inspection project for the **SAT** developing new functionalities and providing maintenance, using as technologies: **Maven** for the generation of Java Web projects, **JSF** with **PrimeFaces** for the view layer, **Spring** Framework for the control or business logic layer, **Hibernate** Framework with **JPA** for the persistence layer, mapping and connection to the Database, generating reports and graphs with quantitative information.

#### **COURSES Y CERTIFICATIONS**

#### Certification JAVA 6

#### **Oracle Certified Profesional Java SE 6 Programmer**

Oracle University

1º March of 2014, Texcoco, Estado de México

## **Diploma DSDSE**

### **Advanced Diploma in Enterprise Software Development**

Universidad Autónoma del Estado de México

1º December of 2023 - Texcoco, Estado de México

## **OnLine Udemy**

- Curso de Linux: todo lo necesario para ser administrador
- Integrando Docker a su infraestructura y servicios
- Angular de cero a experto
- Amazon AWS. Curso básico de Amazon AWS.